<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Channel mix &amp; optimization"
    id="id-803cacba76dc43e6bc77fce536801011"
    documentation="Channel Mix &amp; Optimization is a digital capability used to build and finetune a digital channel portfolio to achieve the customer interactions intended at touchpoints on customer journey maps.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Channel Mix&#xD;&#xA;In order to develop an effective digital channel mix, organizations need to understand the unique features that different digital channels and devices have, and the unique functions they can perform. This understanding can lead to further understanding of how different digital channels and devices best fit specific search, interaction and purchase behaviours defined in the profile of&#xD;&#xA;a target customer segment.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;It is a good idea to start looking at the preferred channels of a target customer segment that are defined in the profile of the customer segment, if one already exists.&#xD;&#xA;Secondary backup channels should also be part of a digital channel mix.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Channel Mix Optimization&#xD;&#xA;The traditional way to optimize a channel mix is to analyse the return on investment, profitability, and/or sales volume for each channel, and reshuffle the channel portfolio according to their financial performance. The primary purpose of the traditional optimization approach is to manage the final results, rather than the customer journey itself, often making the different channels compete against one another. Channel collaboration is much more important for online than for offline, because online channels should collaborate for a customer to complete his end-to-end journey with an improved customer experience. Making multiple digital channels compete against one another would prevent achieving an omni-channel strategy and eventually hinder the digital channels from working together for corporate-level synergy. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;In the digital space, a digital channel portfolio should be optimized against performance indicators and metrics around conversion from one touchpoint and channel of a lower stage, to another touchpoint and channel of an upper stage as planned on a customer journey map, thus promoting collaboration and integration between the different digital channels.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;"/>
