<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Web content management"
    id="id-e12d72ffbac444008a0ba919edb84669"
    documentation="Web content management is a digital capability  used to author, publish and manage web pages, and enable collaboration to create and revise the web pages, even with little understanding of programming languages or mark-up languages.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Web Content Management uses such content as images, audio, videos, or documents that are already stored in the content management system to organize the content into web page templates and to create web pages. The assembled content, web page templates, and complete web pages to be published may be stored in the Web Content Management system. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;All types of content are published onto a web site through Web Content Management. Digital assets may for example be produced through Digital Asset Management processes, stored and maintained in a content repository of the Content Lifecycle Management capability, and published on a web site through a Web Content Management tool.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;A comprehensive content management system such as enterprise content management (ECM) systems, often provides Web Content Management functionalities as a component of the total solution.&#xD;&#xA;The Web Content Management capability includes the following functionalities:&#xD;&#xA;- Web page template management, e.g. product catalogue, merchandising,promotion, blog and community.&#xD;&#xA;- Web page editor with WYSIWYG function.&#xD;&#xA;- Web page metadata editor, e.g. Title tag, Meta tag and Headings.&#xD;&#xA;- SEO management, e.g. HTML code optimization, URL management and sitemap creation.&#xD;&#xA;- Web page version control.&#xD;&#xA;- Collaboration for web site development.&#xD;&#xA;- Web site search.&#xD;&#xA;- Web page access control.&#xD;&#xA;- Rule-based publishing and workflow, e.g. who publishes what, when and where.&#xD;&#xA;- Deployment to multiple Internet domains."/>
