<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Federated access services"
    id="id-8475b1a60fd1400caf711d797c7634e9"
    documentation="Federated Access Management is a digital capability used to authenticate the identity of a user and to authorize the user for access to all digital resources inside and outside the organization, based on trust in a federated access service provider.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;A user’s credentials are always stored with a federated access service provider. When the user logs into an application, the application trusts the federated access service provider to validate the credentials, instead of taking&#xD;&#xA;the credentials from the user.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;As users have immense opportunities to access a wide variety of digital applications in the digital space, the need to share and reuse the data required to authenticate and authorize users inside and outside the organization is ever increasing, in order to provide improved the digital experience when accessing the various digital touchpoints. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Federated Access Management can meet this need by allowing a digital application and a website to perform authentication and authorization of a user through another party that has identity and access rights information,&#xD;&#xA;without actually having or seeing the sensitive, private data.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The fundamental premise of the use cases is that the requested website or system resides in a different security domain than the federated access service provider holding identity and access rights information. The basic idea of the concept of Federated Access Management is that a federated access service provider authenticates and authorizes a user on behalf of the website or application the user is trying to access, and the website or application grants access to the user based on the response from the federated access service provider.&#xD;&#xA;-------------------------------------------&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;OpenID Connect is an open standard that offers a framework for authentication functionality. OpenID Connect is deployed onto OAuth, which is also an open standard that offers a framework for authorization functionality. OAuth, combined with OpenID Connect, provides complete capability of federated authentication and authorization.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;For federated authentication, OpenID allows the server responsible for  authentication to send a user’s web browser an ID token that is to be sent through to a website server the user is trying to access. After performing authentication, OAuth allows the website to ask the server responsible for authorization to send an access token directly back to the website for federated authorization of the user.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;OAuth can be used without OpenID for a website to grant an access to a user whose identity is not known. This is similar to be given a key to a friend’s house. This will allow access to the house, without having to be the friend. Another open standard, SAML (Security Assertion Markup Language), offers a complete framework for both federated authentication and authorization. A SAML-compliant server providing central authentication and authorization services returns a user’s ID and requested URL to the web browser in an encrypted message. The web browser in turn forwards the message to the website.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Whatever standards or technologies are employed to implement Federated Access Management, the overall approach remains the same. Each of the standards and technologies do however provide different functionalities to be able to meet different business requirements and needs. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;In a SAML environment, a strong encryption-based digital signature is used to verify the integrity of federated authentication and authorization, instead of the identity and access tokens used in OpenID Connect and OAuth. The websites registered by a central authentication and authorization server can only participate in SAML-based federated access management, whereas any websites compliant to OpenID Connect and OAuth specifications can participate in OpenID and OAuth-based federation.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This is why SAML is more widely used in enterprise digital environments, while OpenID and OAuth are commonly used in digital environments that are more open.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;"/>
