<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Customer loyalty management"
    id="id-dcbf46fa25f447069e659307077cf79f"
    documentation="Customer loyalty management is a digital capability used to plan and implement a loyalty program to increase brand loyalty of customers. It includes abilities to gather and analyse data representing customer loyalty, to plan and measure their loyalty to a brand. A loyalty program is used to reward and thus encourage loyal buying behaviours by using a membership structure and membership benefits.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Customer Loyalty Management concept has been around for many decades. Common functionalities of the capability include the following:&#xD;&#xA;- Member classification.&#xD;&#xA;- Membership card management, i.e. physical loyalty cards, gift cards, or digital cards.&#xD;&#xA;- Member credential management: whether social media credential can be shared.&#xD;&#xA;- Member referral tracking.&#xD;&#xA;- Membership portal, web and mobile.&#xD;&#xA;- Points management: how points are earned and spent.&#xD;&#xA;- Other benefits management: discounts, premium contents, events, etc.&#xD;&#xA;- Partnership: how points are earned and shared across partner networks.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The key to the success of Customer Loyalty Management does not lie in the loyalty program itself, because recent loyalty programs are all quite similar and customers don’t find any significant differentiation among them that drives loyalty to a specific brand. The key to the success of Customer Loyalty Management rather lies in its integration with other digital capabilities.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Here is an example. Let’s presume a company interacts with a Gold member for product repairs through Interaction Tracking &amp; Management. They then discover that the customer has been at the final stage of the conversion funnel longer than the pre-defined waiting days in Conversion Rate Optimization. As email has previously been identified as the customer’s preferred communication channel in the Customer Preference Management, the company sends a marketing offer via email in Marketing Offer Management. This marketing offer is only available to Gold members. For this business scenario to work, the following six digital capabilities should be integrated seamlessly without swivel chair integration: &#xD;&#xA;- Interaction Tracking &amp; Management&#xD;&#xA;- Customer Loyalty Management&#xD;&#xA;- Conversion Rate  Optimization&#xD;&#xA;- Marketing Offer Management&#xD;&#xA;- Email Marketing&#xD;&#xA;- Customer Preference Management. &#xD;&#xA;Although this might be a very sophisticated scenario, this level of integration is the best way to give an  organization a competitive advantage as this integration practice can’t be copied easily by competitors."/>
