<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Business continuity services"
    id="id-20cac7b0672744f38d40fc95062f1ef1"
    documentation="Digital Continuity Management is a digital capability used to ensure that digital business continues if availability solutions fail and cannot restore digital capabilities because of such natural disasters and disastrous external&#xD;&#xA;incidents as fire, floods, earthquakes, strikes and war. The capability encompasses the assessment of the impact of such events on digital business, continuity planning, solution implementation and communication with  users. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Availability management solutions such as system clustering and local backup cannot ensure the availability of the digital systems with such an extreme incident. On-Demand Provisioning Services includes an ability to provision new or more resources when there is an availability issue. When  such an extreme incident occurs and the production data centre cannot provide services for digital business any more, Digital Continuity Management should enable critical digital capabilities to recover so that critical digital business processes can continue.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Disaster recovery solutions should be focused on the critical digital capabilities rather than all the digital capabilities. You can simply back up applications and data supporting the critical digital capabilities into removable storage media and keep them offsite. The most common way is however to set up a separate, remote data centre for disaster recovery purpose on-premises or on the Cloud, and electronically replicate applications and data to the data centre on a regular basis. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The frequency of replication depends on the Recovery Point Objective (RPO) metric that describes the maximum-targeted period in which data might be lost from a disaster. If the RPO is for example one day, the replication must be made at intervals of 24 hours or less. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Recovery Time Objective (RTO) is another metric frequently used for disaster recovery. It represents the targeted period within which a system supporting a digital capability must be recovered after a disaster, in order to&#xD;&#xA;avoid unacceptable consequences associated with a disruption in digital business. If the RTO is for example one day, the system must be recovered within 24 hours or less.&#xD;&#xA;  "/>
