<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Master data management"
    id="id-841b39f9b04f4d86becf6b0f5a5c01a0"
    documentation="Master data represents critical business objects, such as customers, products, suppliers, sales, divisions, costs and many other business entities of the organization.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Master data is non-transactional, static data used to create transactional data. Customer data and product data, which are master data, are for example used to create a customer order, which is transactional data. Customer order data would have a product code and name, quantity of the product ordered, customer name, delivery address, etc. Most of the data fields on a customer order are captured from customer and product master data, while very few data fields are created by customer key-in.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Without rich master data, rich transactional data is not possible, which leads to poor analytical data. Master data is therefore at the core of all enterprise data.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Master Data Management (MDM) is a digital capability used to collect, aggregate, match, consolidate, quality-assure, persist and distribute masterdata, to ensure consistency in data use by different digital applications.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Master Data Management has been around as a critical component for data integration even before the contemporary digital age began. It has helped the organization identify and manage the same business entities of different systems in a consistent way. They could for example identify the same customer in different systems and serve the customer across the different systems seamlessly.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;In the digital age, Master Data Management is becoming even more challenging because different master data of the same business entities is proliferating in new digital channels, new devices, social websites, and SaaS applications, as well as traditional internal systems. Master data should therefore be integrated or consolidated more actively across the organization to function as master data properly.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Unfortunately, this is not the case in many organizations. Product data used on social media is for example not necessarily identified in the trusted product master data that is used by marketing, sales, customer services and finance departments. This can lead to inconsistent customer communication that can actually undermine sales or customer services.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Big Data, Customer Insight, and Customer Segmentation capabilities may be able to produce plenty of insights into a customer. Without knowing exactly who the customer is in the trusted customer master data, the insights can however not be used for social interaction, or digital marketing in the frontoffice.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Customer data and product data are the most important master data of all. Any organization can establish an effective Master Data Management capability by defining a standard customer and product data model, and consolidating all enterprise data similar to these into the centralized, standard customer and product data models. With proper access control to the master data and regular data cleansing activities, the robust foundation for Master Data Management required for digital business will be in place.&#xD;&#xA;"/>
